I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
Yeah, there was quite a bit of talk about it on the way here from Lubinheigen.
Yep, how creepy!
Are you talking about the sorcerer who appeared on the new road?
I heard about that.
They say it can summon wolves to be its puppets.
They attack travelers in order to consume their blood.
No way.
It's no joke. You better be careful.
In Lubinheigen, I heard the rumors from a member of the Church.
An entire caravan was attacked two weeks ago.
Whoa, creepy... Really creepy, isn't it?
I'm gonna drown this fear with more booze.
Couldn't hurt for me to take note.
I pray, for your sake, that the sorcerer isn't a woman.
Why's that?
You're easily fooled by women,
and slow to recover when you get hurt.
You've been drinking more heavily ever since that day.
H-Hey...
It's the talk of nearly every tavern we visit,
the Medio Trading deal.
Men really are dumb creatures.
Well, excuse me for being dumb.
Wolf and a Proper Balance
What an inconsiderate town this is!
They close the tavern far too early!
This place is a satellite of the Church stronghold Lubinheigen, after all.
Be thankful they let someone run a tavern for travelers at all.
So this town's only interested in living a humble life and offering prayers to God?
It's best known for the citizens putting you to sleep with talk about how profound the latest sermon was.
Hard to believe anyone could enjoy a life like that.
We'll head to Lubinheigen once I sell the pepper and purchase new goods.
Is it a large town?
Yeah, bigger than Pazzio.
It's a city rather than a town.
It's a busy place with lots of street stalls.
Will there be any apples?
I'm not sure about raw apples.
This is the season for preserves.
Preserves?
I'm not talking about pickled goods.
Fruits preserved in honey.
Oh?
Not just apples, either.
Pears preserved in honey taste good, too.
And they started doing peaches recently.
Peaches...
Thinly sliced peaches are stacked inside a barrel.
The best products even have figs and almonds inside.
Ginger is added after honey is poured on the peaches.
They stew for two months like that.
The sweet sensation that fills your mouth is unlike anything in this world.
It's not surprising that the Church was considering banning the stuff.
Hey, you're drooling.
You're not toying with me, are you?
I'm not, but peach preserves are a product of the wealthy.
You don't really find them just up for sale.
But what if we do? Could we buy them if we do?
O-Okay, I'll buy some for you.
You have to!
Only a little, though.
That's a promise, okay?
H-Hey, are you listening to me?
Let's go.
Let's go right now.
Go where?
Where else? We'll go to the inn, get our cart, and go to Whatever Trading Company.
We're going to wake the person there, get good money for our pepper, and head to Lubinheigen.
Wait a second. At this hour of the night?
It might sell out soon.
That would be a total catastrophe.
The market probably won't have them on sale in the first place, let alone sell out!
Peaches and honey... That's hard to believe.
Mind-boggling, even.
Don't treat this like a sure thing.
However...
It's hard to give up pears.
The pastor's sermons moved our hearts quite a bit.
It was literally a blessing from God.
His words gave us motivation to strive for greater service to the Lord.
Well, I rambled on a bit there, but shall we start discussing our business?
Yes, let's.
What do you have to offer today?
This is it.
Pepper, is it?
You know your goods.
It's the scent.
Impressive.
Not at all. It's just a matter of experience.
You wouldn't happen to have your own scale, would you?
I don't have one, but I have faith in God.
In any case, what bad luck for me.
The demand for pepper has increased significantly as of late.
If you had come a week earlier,
I could have taken it off your hands for nothing at all!
Sounds like I came in at just the right time.
Indeed. Let's proceed with the weighing of the pepper.
Yes, please.
Let's see, we'll need paper and ink.
Wait just a moment, please.
What is it?
I'm thirsty.
You'll have to wait.
Will water be okay?
I have some wine as well.
Oh, water, if you please.
Not a problem.
That's forty-five measures' worth, then.
Where does this pepper come from?
Ramapata, in the Kingdom of Leedon.
Milone Trading conducted the import.
Ramapata is famous for its spices,
and the certificate looks to be genuine.
How does one Lumione gold coin per measure sound to you?
What's the exchange rate for Lumione gold coins?
Do you want the value in Trenni silver coins?
Yes.
Thirty-two and five-sixths Trenni silver coins.
That's the current exchange rate.
I accept the offer.
Oh, in that case...
Is something wrong?
I feel dizzy...
A-Are you all right?
Y-Yes...
Do you feel better?
Yes, thank you.
A long journey will tire even a strong man.
I'll bring some goat milk for you.
Sir?
These scales still seem tilted to my eyes.
Do they look that way to you?
No, that certainly couldn't be the case.
I know it couldn't, but...
Whoa!
Hey, are you all right?
My eyes don't seem to be working correctly.
It seems that what I drank was wine, not water.
Isn't that right, sir?
As the proverb says, "The rowdier the pub, the more sober its master."
I see now.
The secret to success is being the only sober one, eh?
It seems I'm drunk on the same wine as my companion.
I doubt we'll remember some of the things we've seen and heard here.
However, drunkards have been known to demand unreasonable things.
W-What do you—
You'll pay the initial sum you offered, the amount you were to profit from this deal, and, let's see...
You'll allow me to buy double all that on loan.
Double? That's out of the question.
Oh, that's too bad.
Feels like the wine is wearing off.
Let's talk about the merchandise.
Given the large sum involved here, why don't you pay me in high quality weapons and armor?
Arms, you say?
They're always a good bet for turning a safe profit.
I can get the loan back to you quickly that way.
I imagine you've got arms bound for Lubinheigen, don't you?
Arms, you say...
You must have connections to other trading companies in Lubinheigen, right?
Selling them there will balance out the books.
What say you?
Thank you very much.
Could you arrange for the goods immediately?
I hope to leave for Lubinheigen as soon as possible.
V-Very well.
What about the appraisal?
I'll leave that to you. After all, I have faith in God.
Poor man.
I'm surprised you noticed.
I'm beautiful, I'm wise, and my tail's fur is sleek.
But my eyes and ears are also keen.
I noticed as soon as I set foot inside this place.
Did you?
What's that supposed to mean?
What's gotten into you?
Experience may lead to self-confidence, but pride goes before a fall.
Didn't Chloe teach you that?
You're absolutely right.
You fool!
Don't go sulking about it!
Learn from the experience and move on.
Oil?
Yes, I hear it's good for grooming my tail.
Can you buy some for me when we reach the next town?
The clothes you're wearing now, your change of clothes, your comb,
your traveling expenses, food, and the huge amount of wine... have you bothered to add all that up?
There's the head tax I have to pay every time we enter a town, as well.
Surely you're not telling me you can't do sums.
I can do addition.
I'm good at subtraction, too.
In that case, add up what you've used.
If you're such a wise wolf, you should be able to work out my answer from that.
Indeed I can.
You'll buy me some for sure.
Just look what happens to the wits of the proud wise wolf when she has too much wine.
I'm not drunk, you know.
Idiot! What are you...
Just kidding.
Geez...
You shouldn't underestimate me.
Surely you don't think I missed how much you gained
from taking advantage of that appraiser's weakness?
Will you buy me some oil?
Do you know how much money you still owe me?
A hundred and forty silver coins.
I'm sure you realize that's a small fortune.
How do you expect me to spend even more on luxuries?
What? You want me to repay my debt that badly?
Of. Course. I. Do.
So that's how you've been thinking.
What do you mean?
Well, I suppose if I pay my debts, that makes me a free wolf.
Oh, well. I suppose I should pay you back as soon as possible and head back north myself.
I'm accustomed to solitude, anyway.
We didn't decide the due date for payment.
It'll be fine so long as I get it before we reach the northern woods.
Will that do?
Yes, I should think I'll be able to repay you by the time we reach the north country.
And it's my intention to pay you back with interest.
In other words, the more I borrow, the greater profit for you. You see?
Oil, huh?
Yes. You can put it on my tab,
so could you buy some for me?
It's a deal.
Thank you.
What a beautiful day for grooming.
By the way, you got quite the discount on those goods, didn't you?
Why do you want to know?
Well, I wouldn't want to sponge off a traveling merchant who's barely scraping by.
Arms sell fast in Lubinheigen, but there are many merchants who sell them.
There isn't a lot of profit to be had,
so getting a lower price can only do so much.
But since you bought this much, will you not make some profit?
Well, it should cover the cost of some oil.
That's good to hear.
You know, in comparison to this load, spices are divine.
Did you have a taste?
I'm not like you, you glutton.
I'm talking about profit.
Why don't you trade spices again, then?
Their prices in Lubinheigen aren't much higher than in Poroson.
I'd take a loss from selling spices due to tariffs.
Then give it up, I say.
If I could sell other commodities at the same profit margin as spices,
I'd be able to open a store in no time at all.
Surely there's something.
Jewels and gold seem like they'd sell well.
Those kinds of items aren't too profitable in Lubinheigen.
Why's that?
The tariff is way too high.
They levy serious taxes on all but a certain group of merchants.
There's no business to be had there.
Why are certain merchants exempt?
They have ties with the Church.
They bring gold bars to Lubinheigen, and those bars are inscribed with the Holy Seal.
Once the gold becomes blessed that way, it fetches an absurdly high price.
The Church receives generous donations in return.
What a corrupt system.
That's why they're extremely strict about smuggling.
Smuggled gold would probably sell for twice the market price, but there are too many risks involved.
There aren't any idiots dumb enough to take their chances.
Could gold really be that hard to hide?
Their cargo inspections are pretty thorough.
What happens to those who are caught?
They'll cut off your right hand, at the very least.
It just isn't worth the risk.
Well, your business is doing well enough. There's nothing wrong with making steady coin.
I tend to agree, but a certain someone's spending all my hard-earned money.
You better be careful along the way.
It looks like mercenaries have arrived from the north.
Mercenaries?
Yeah.
Traveling on this path would be suicide, then.
Yeah, they spot their prey faster than a hawk on the wing
and take everything of value, down to the leaves on the turnips.
They're armed with long spears, too.
Even I have stories to tell about the trouble they've caused.
I was surprised to hear that they've come this far south.
Same as us merchants, they only move based on profit and loss.
Well, it's pointless to think about it here.
In any case, let's head to Lubinheigen by using the new side road.
You're not afraid of pagan sorcerers, are you?
No.
They say there are packs of wolves on the side route.
They're easier to deal with than humans.
At least I can reason with them.
I'll leave the negotiations to you, then.
There's no one in sight.
Rumors of a thing usually hold more power than the thing itself.
How boring. I'm going to take a nap.
You'll notice wolves approaching even if you're asleep, right?
Of course I will!
It'll be a hassle if they surround us.
You worry too much.
Most animals are quite aware, be they sleeping or awake.
It's only you humans who are defenseless in slumber.
You'd be more convincing if you snored less.
I don't snore!
Well, it's not that loud, I suppose.
I told you I don't snore!
Okay, okay.
I don't snore at all!
I get the message.
What is it?
I'll let you handle these negotiations.
Who's ahead of us?
The kind of human that I despise.
Are you talking about the sorcerer?
Sheep?
Is that the sorcerer we've heard about?
What was all that about?
It's a ritual for when you meet a shepherd.
At least we know he isn't a sorcerer.
I'm Lawrence, a traveling merchant.
This is my partner, Holo.
I'd like to ask the shepherd I've met under God's guidance to offer prayers for our safety.
With pleasure.
Next Episode: "Wolf and the Shepherd's Lamb."